WETA Women of Achievement Oral History Project OHP008
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
WETA Women of Achievement Oral History Project
1979-1985
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
WETA (Radio station: Arlington, Va.)
OHP008
7.5 Linear feet
5 Boxes
Arrangement
Series 1: Transcripts' Scope and Contents Materials in this series include transcripts for 13 of 39 interviews. Interviews are for the following recordings: 08-01A, 08-01B, 08-02A, 08-02B, 08-04A, 08-04B, 08-05A, 08-05B, 08-07A, 08-07B, 08-09A, 08-09B, and 08-15. Series 2: Interviews Scope and Contents Materials in this series include master and patron access copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are at least two copies for all audio recordings. boxes 4 and 5 contain original reel-to-reel recordings.
Biographical / Historical
Formed in 1953, the Greater Washington Educational Television Association transmitted their first broadcast in 1961 as a non-commercial educational Public Broadcasting System (PBS) member. Among the programs produced by WETA that are distributed nationally by PBS are the PBS News Hour, Washington Week, and several nationally broadcast cultural and documentary programs, such as the Ken Burns' documentaries and "A Capitol Fourth."
Custodial History
WETA conducted these interviews between 1979 and 1985 and donated the tapes and transcripts to the Library in 1983. There is no deed of gift for the collection, but correspondence in the control file indicated their legal transfer to the Library.
Scope and Contents
Between 1979 and 1985, WETA-FM conducted a total of 56 "luncheon series" oral history interviews with notable women in the greater Washington, D.C. area. All interviews were a part of a series entitled "Women of Achievement." Each interview is approximately 45 minutes to an hour long and topics included their life and work experiences. Interviewees were chosen for their achievements in a wide range of fields, including community volunteering, business, and the arts. The project's director was Elizabeth Campbell, Vice President of Community Affairs. 08-41 is labeled "Audience Questions" and appears to be from an event held by WETA.
Oral History; Women; Businesspeople; Arts; Political activists; Educators
- Series 1: Transcripts
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in this series include transcripts for 13 of 39 interviews. Interviews are for the following recordings: 08-01A, 08-01B, 08-02A, 08-02B, 08-04A, 08-04B, 08-05A, 08-05B, 08-07A, 08-07B, 08-09A, 08-09B, and 08-15.
  - M. Jane Evans, 1981 October 14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Patricia Roberts Harris, 1981 November 11 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mary Day, 1981 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Thelma Lavine, 1982 February 10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Gladys M. Sprinkle, 1982 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Catherine Filene Shouse, 1982 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Margaret Rockwell, 1982 October 13 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Zelda Fichandler, 1982 November 10 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Floretta Dukes McKenzie, 1983 February 9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Candace Johnson, 1983 March 9 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Beverly Benner Cassara, 1983 October 12 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Carol Lescaris, 1983 November 7 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Sarah McClendon, 1984 November 14 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Series 2: Interviews
  Materials in this series include master and patron access copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are at least two copies for all audio recordings. Boxes 4 and 5 contain original reel-to-reel recordings.
  - M. Jane Evans, 1981 October 14 (Box 2, Folder 08-01A)
  - Patricia Roberts Harris, 1981 November 11 (Box 2, Folder 08-01B)
  - Mary Day, 1981 December 9 (Box 2, Folder 08-02A)
  - Thelma Z. Lavine, 1982 February 10 (Box 2, Folder 08-02B)
  - Rita C. Davidson, 1982 March 10 (Box 2, Folder 08-03A)
  - Eloise Greenfield, 1982 April 14 (Box 2, Folder 08-03B)
  - Gladys M. Sprinkle, 1982 May 12 (Box 2, Folder 08-04A)
  - Catherine Filene Shouse, 1982 June 16 (Box 2, Folder 08-04B)
  - Margaret Rockwell, 1982 October 13 (Box 2, Folder 08-05A)
  - Zelda Fichandler, 1982 November 10 (Box 2, Folder 08-05B)
  - Julia M. Walsh, 1982 December 8 (Box 2, Folder 08-06A)
  - Barbara M. Watson, 1983 January 10 (Box 2, Folder 08-06B)
  - Floretta Dukes McKenzie, 1983 February 9 (Box 2, Folder 08-07A)
  - Candace Johnson, 1983 March 9 (Box 2, Folder 08-07B)
  - Mary Ann Lundgren, 1983 April 13 (Box 2, Folder 08-08A)
  - Barbara S. Thomas, 1983 May 9 (Box 2, Folder 08-08B)
  - Beverly Benner Cassara, 1983 October 12 (Box 2, Folder 08-09A)
  - Carol Lescaris, 1983 November 7 (Box 2, Folder 08-09B)
  - Sharon Allison Moseley, 1983 December 12 (Box 2, Folder 08-10)
  - Holly Martin Townsend, 1984 February 13 (Box 2, Folder 08-11A)
  - Anne Hessing Cahn, 1984 March 12 (Box 2, Folder 08-11B)
  - Peggy Cooper Cafritz, 1984 April 9 (Box 2, Folder 08-12)
  - Dorothy Robins-Mowry, 1984 May 14 (Box 2, Folder 08-13)
  - Diana Lady Dougan, 1984 September 24 (Box 2, Folder 08-14)
  - Sarah McClendon, 1984 November 14 (Box 2, Folder 08-15)
  - Elaine R. Walter, 1984 December 11 (Box 2, Folder 08-16)
  - Mary Hatwood Futrell, 1985 January 8 (Box 2, Folder 08-17)
  - Naomi Lynn Hurwitz Gerber, 1985 February 12 (Box 3, Folder 08-18)
  - Anne Clinton Seymour, 1985 March 12 (Box 3, Folder 08-19)
  - Alice Callis Hunter, 1985 April 9 (Box 3, Folder 08-20)
  - Carmella LaSpada, 1985 May 14 (Box 3, Folder 08-21)
  - Sharon Percy Rockefeller, 1985 June 11 (Box 3, Folder 08-22)
  - Wilhelmina Holladay, 1983 December 12 (Box 3, Folder 08-23)
  - Effie Barry, 1979 October 10 (Box 3, Folder 08-24)
  - Anne Crutcher, 1979 November 14 (Box 3, Folder 08-25)
  - Frankie Hewitt, 1979 December 12 (Box 3, Folder 08-26)
  - Josefina Magno, 1980 January 9 (Box 3, Folder 08-27)
  - Antonia Chavse, 1980 February 13 (Box 3, Folder 08-28)
  - Flaxie Pinkett, 1980 March 12 (Box 3, Folder 08-29)
  - Estelle Ramey, 1980 April 9 (Box 3, Folder 08-30)
  - Perdita Huston, 1980 May 14 (Box 3, Folder 08-31)
  - Mary Marshall, 1980 October 8 (Box 3, Folder 08-32)
  - Lynette Taylor, 1980 November 12 (Box 3, Folder 08-33)
  - Abby Smith, 1980 December 10 (Box 3, Folder 08-34)
  - Lorraine A. Williams, 1981 January 14 (Box 3, Folder 08-35)
  - Irene Tinker, 1981 February 11 (Box 3, Folder 08-36)
  - Marian Edelman, 1981 March 11 (Box 3, Folder 08-37)
  - Marie D. Gadsden, 1981 April 8 (Box 3, Folder 08-38)
  - Marta Istomin, 1981 May 13 (Box 3, Folder 08-39)
  - M. Jane Evans, 1981 October 14 (Box 4, Folder 08-01A)
  - Patricia Roberts Harris, 1981 November 11 (Box 4, Folder 08-01B)
  - Mary Day, 1981 December 9 (Box 4, Folder 08-02A)
  - Thelma Z. Lavine, 1982 February 10 (Box 4, Folder 08-02B)
  - Rita C. Davidson, 1982 March 10 (Box 4, Folder 08-03A)
  - Eloise Greenfield, 1982 April 14 (Box 4, Folder 08-03B)
  - Gladys M. Sprinkle, 1982 May 12 (Box 4, Folder 08-04A)
  - Catherine Filene Shouse, 1982 June 16 (Box 4, Folder 08-04B)
  - Margaret Rockwell, 1982 October 13 (Box 4, Folder 08-05A)
  - Zelda Fichandler, 1982 November 10 (Box 4, Folder 08-05B)
  - Julia M. Walsh, 1982 December 8 (Box 4, Folder 08-06A)
  - Barbara M. Watson, 1983 January 10 (Box 4, Folder 08-06B)
  - Floretta Dukes McKenzie, 1983 February 9 (Box 4, Folder 08-07A)
  - Candace Johnson, 1983 March 9 (Box 4, Folder 08-07B)
  - Mary Ann Lundgren, 1983 April 13 (Box 4, Folder 08-08A)
  - Barbara S. Thomas, 1983 May 9 (Box 4, Folder 08-08B)
  - Beverly Benner Cassara, 1983 October 12 (Box 4, Folder 08-09A)
  - Carol Lescaris, 1983 November 7 (Box 4, Folder 08-09B)
  - Sharon Allison Moseley, 1983 December 12 (Box 4, Folder 08-10)
  - Holly Martin Townsend, 1984 February 13 (Box 4, Folder 08-11A)
  - Anne Hessing Cahn, 1984 March 12 (Box 4, Folder 08-11B)
  - Peggy Cooper Cafritz, 1984 April 9 (Box 4, Folder 08-12)
  - Dorothy Robins-Mowry, 1984 May 14 (Box 4, Folder 08-13)
  - Diana Lady Dougan, 1984 September 24 (Box 4, Folder 08-14)
  - Sarah McClendon, 1984 November 14 (Box 4, Folder 08-15)
  - Elaine R. Walter, 1984 December 11 (Box 4, Folder 08-16)
  - Mary Hatwood Futrell, 1985 January 8 (Box 4, Folder 08-17)
  - Naomi Lynn Hurwitz Gerber, 1985 February 12 (Box 4, Folder 08-18)
  - Anne Clinton Seymour, 1985 March 12 (Box 4, Folder 08-19)
  - Alice Callis Hunter, 1985 April 9 (Box 4, Folder 08-20)
  - Carmella LaSpada, 1985 May 14 (Box 4, Folder 08-21)
  - Sharon Percy Rockefeller, 1985 June 11 (Box 4, Folder 08-22)
  - Wilhelmina Holladay, 1983 December 12 (Box 4, Folder 08-23)
  - Effie Barry, 1979 October 10 (Box 4, Folder 08-24)
  - Anne Crutcher, 1979 November 14 (Box 4, Folder 08-25)
  - Frankie Hewitt, 1979 December 12 (Box 5, Folder 08-26)
  - Josefina Magno, 1980 January 9 (Box 5, Folder 08-27)
  - Antonia Chavse, 1980 February 13 (Box 5, Folder 08-28)
  - Flaxie Pinkett, 1980 March 12 (Box 5, Folder 08-29)
  - Estelle Ramey, 1980 April 9 (Box 5, Folder 08-30)
  - Perdita Huston, 1980 May 14 (Box 5, Folder 08-31)
  - Mary Marshall, 1980 October 8 (Box 5, Folder 08-32)
  - Lynette Taylor, 1980 November 12 (Box 5, Folder 08-33)
  - Abby Smith, 1980 December 10 (Box 5, Folder 08-34)
  - Lorraine A. Williams, 1981 January 14 (Box 5, Folder 08-35)
  - Irene Tinker, 1981 February 11 (Box 5, Folder 08-36)
  - Marian Edelman, 1981 March 11 (Box 5, Folder 08-37)
  - Marie D. Gadsden, 1981 April 8 (Box 5, Folder 08-38)
  - Marta Istomin, 1981 May 13 (Box 5, Folder 08-39)
  - Ann Kahn?, 1984 March 12 (Box 5, Folder 08-40)
  - Audience Questions (Box 5, Folder 08-41)